{
  "questions": [
    {
      "questionId": 1,
      "question": "Which of these best describes an array?",
      "category": "Arrays",
      "mcq1": "A data structure that shows a hierarchical behavior",
      "mcq2": "Container of objects of similar types",
      "mcq3": "Arrays are immutable once initialised",
      "mcq4": "Array is not a data structure",
      "mcq5": "None of these."
    },
    {
      "questionId": 2,
      "question": "How do you initialize an array in C?",
      "category": "Arrays",
      "mcq1": "int arr[3] = (1,2,3);",
      "mcq2": "int arr(3) = {1,2,3};",
      "mcq3": "int arr[3] = {1,2,3};",
      "mcq4": "int arr(3) = (1,2,3);",
      "mcq5": "None of these."
    },
    {
      "questionId": 3,
      "question": "What are the disadvantages of arrays?",
      "category": "Arrays",
      "mcq1": "Data structure like queue or stack cannot be implemented",
      "mcq2": "There are chances of wastage of memory space if elements inserted in an array are lesser than the allocated size",
      "mcq3": "Index value of an array can be negative",
      "mcq4": "Elements are sequentially accessed",
      "mcq5": "None of these."
    },
    {
      "questionId": 4,
      "question": "In general, the index of the first element in an array is __________",
      "category": "Arrays",
      "mcq1": "0",
      "mcq2": "-1",
      "mcq3": "2",
      "mcq4": "1",
      "mcq5": "None of these."
    },
    {
      "questionId": 5,
      "question": "Elements in an array are accessed ______",
      "category": "Arrays",
      "mcq1": "randomly",
      "mcq2": "sequentially",
      "mcq3": "exponentially",
      "mcq4": "logarithmically",
      "mcq5": "None of these."
    },
    {
      "questionId": 6,
      "question": "Assuming int is of 4bytes, what is the size of int arr[15];?",
      "category": "Arrays",
      "mcq1": "15",
      "mcq2": "19",
      "mcq3": "11",
      "mcq4": "60",
      "mcq5": "None of these."
    },
    {
      "questionId": 7,
      "question": "Which of the following concepts make extensive use of arrays?",
      "category": "Arrays",
      "mcq1": " Binary trees",
      "mcq2": "Scheduling of processes",
      "mcq3": "Caching",
      "mcq4": "Spatial locality0",
      "mcq5": "None of these."
    },
    {
      "questionId": 8,
      "question": "'OS' computer abbreviation usually means?",
      "category": "CS Fundamentals",
      "mcq1": " Order of Significance",
      "mcq2": "Open Software",
      "mcq3": "Operating System",
      "mcq4": "Optical Sensor",
      "mcq5": "None of these."
    },
    {
      "questionId": 9,
      "question": "What is part of a database that holds only one type of information?",
      "category": "CS Fundamentals",
      "mcq1": "Report",
      "mcq2": "Field",
      "mcq3": "Record",
      "mcq4": "File",
      "mcq5": "None of these."
    },
    {
      "questionId": 10,
      "question": "DB' computer abbreviation usually means?",
      "category": "CS Fundamentals",
      "mcq1": "Database",
      "mcq2": "Double Byte",
      "mcq3": "Data Block",
      "mcq4": "Driver Boot",
      "mcq5": "None of these."
    }
  ],
  "answers": [
    {
      "answerId": 1,
      "correctAns": "mcq2",
      "questionId": 1
    },
    {
      "answerId": 2,
      "correctAns": "mcq3",
      "questionId": 2
    },
    {
      "answerId": 3,
      "correctAns": "mcq2",
      "questionId": 3
    },
    {
      "answerId": 4,
      "correctAns": "mcq1",
      "questionId": 4
    },
    {
      "answerId": 5,
      "correctAns": "mcq2",
      "questionId": 5
    },
    {
      "answerId": 6,
      "correctAns": "mcq4",
      "questionId": 6
    },
    {
      "answerId": 7,
      "correctAns": "mcq4",
      "questionId": 7
    },
    {
      "answerId": 8,
      "correctAns": "mcq3",
      "questionId": 8
    },
    {
      "answerId": 9,
      "correctAns": "mcq2",
      "questionId": 9
    },
    {
      "answerId": 10,
      "correctAns": "mcq1",
      "questionId": 10
    }
  ]
}
